<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2016 on My personal notes</title>
    <link>https://voloda.bazilisek.net/year/2016/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2016 on My personal notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://voloda.bazilisek.net/year/2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyclocomputer Garmin Edge 520 - experience</title>
      <link>https://voloda.bazilisek.net/2016/10/cyclocomputer-garmin-edge-520-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voloda.bazilisek.net/2016/10/cyclocomputer-garmin-edge-520-experience/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I bought Garmin Edge 520 couple weeks ago. There are quite a few reviews on internet so this is not intended to be a general review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is rather few comments on features I didn&amp;rsquo;t find described elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://voloda.bazilisek.net/img/mix/edge520.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Garmin Edge 520&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;device-configuration&#34;&gt;Device configuration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was used from Sigma Rox 9.0 that the configuration is done with convenience in a related software.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This served also for the configuration backup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unfortunately most of the setup for Garmin Edge 520 needs to be done manually on the device itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For initial setup this is pretty time consuming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;navigation-features&#34;&gt;Navigation features&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As written in reviews the device does not have real navigation. Instead you can upload a &lt;code&gt;.gpx&lt;/code&gt; file and device will navigate you on a route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I used this link to generate Open Street maps for device:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Map generation can be found here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://garmin.openstreetmap.nl/&#34;&gt;http://http://garmin.openstreetmap.nl/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Route from &lt;a href=&#34;http://ridewithgps.com&#34;&gt;Ride With GPS&lt;/a&gt; seems to work great even in Czech Republic.

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It takes some time before you get used to how the navigation works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recently I was able to plan a group ride for 150km in mountains which worked very well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The only downside is that it took more than a minute before the device read the course and started to navigate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We made a small side trip and the device found itself back on the course once we joined the original plan.w&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is very convenient to watch for example elevation profile during a ride.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall the navigation is basically a race against a virtual partner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;strava-segments&#34;&gt;Strava Segments&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I liked &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.strava.com&#34;&gt;Strava&lt;/a&gt; segments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starred segments appear automatically on the device if you have Strava premium membership.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each segment can be in the device configured against whom you compete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There two related challenges:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When using course navigation or Garmin Connect workouts segments are disabled by default.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPS precision can start/end the segment in a little bit different location than Strava will later evaluate it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
